# William C. Finneran

484-345-0572 | finneranbilly@gmail.com | Washington, D.C. linkedin.com/in/william-c-finneran-iv-8790a8104/ | github.com/wfinneran

#### **Summary:**

Supply Chain Analyst with a strong background in data analytics, supply chain, and information systems. Experienced in Python, SQL Server, JavaScript, and various other technologies. Passionate to further utilize and build upon my technical skills in order to solve complex business problems. Polished communicator confident with transforming business requirements into technical solutions and explaining details to stakeholders.

#### **EDUCATION:**

**George Washington University** 

**Data Analytics Bootcamp** 

The Pennsylvania State University

Smeal College of Business

Bachelor of Science, Supply Chain & Information Systems

September 2019 – Present Washington, D.C. Class of 2017 University Park, PA

### **TECHNICAL ABILITIES:**

• Programming Languages: SQL, Python, Java, R

• Front-end Languages: JQuery, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Databases: MS SQL Server, mySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Business Intelligence Tools: Microsoft Power BI, Tableau

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

**Total Wine & More** 

Analyst, Supply Chain Solutions

August 2019 – Present Bethesda, MD

- Gather user requirements, build SQL queries, create data models, and design/develop reports and tools for both the Supply Chain and Merchandising departments
- Update, verify, analyze and distribute supply chain reports to business users
- Transitioned 100+ existing supply chain reports from Microsoft Access into Microsoft Excel based tools powered by MS SQL Server to accommodate new external business partners
- Designed, own, and maintain 20+ sales and inventory reporting dashboards using Microsoft Power BI

**Total Wine & More** 

Associate, Market Management

May 2018 – July 2019

Bethesda, MD

- Oversaw forecasting, procurement, and inventory management of all national brand product in Washington State
- Modified forecasting tool to calculate storage and interest costs on long term purchases, saved over \$100k during Q4 2018
- Took initiative to create reports that are universally applicable for different software systems to increase data sharing and improve documentation with external partners
- Increased gross margin 1.02% for wine and spirits in 2018 (Washington State)

**Total Wine & More** 

June 2017 - April 2018

Bethesda, MD

Senior Specialist, Market Management

- Led the Market Management Team with an in-stock rating of 99.70% for the Washington market
- Grew year to date sales in the Washington market by 10.15% through strategic planning and quantitative forecasting
- Reduced the number of holiday specific items out of stock by 18.15% through creating an algorithm to forecast Q4
  demand this tool is now used company-wide
- Created reports and tools in Microsoft Excel to improve business processes by automating inefficient tasks resulting in reduced labor time and number of errors

## **LEADERSHIP:**

**Total Wine & More** 

August 2017 - Present

Supply Chain Intern Ambassador

Bethesda, MD

Selected to represent Total Wine & More at college career fairs to recruit and interview summer intern candidates

#### **Penn State Lion Link**

January 2019 - Present

Mentor

Advise and guide Penn State seniors searching for career advice in Supply Chain and Analytics

#### **PERSONAL INTERESTS:**

• Golf, NFL and college football, U.S. and world history, traveling, investing, and fashion